A Guide to the Papers of John Randolph of Roanoke, 1781-1860, [n.d.]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of John Randolph of Roanoke 1781-1860, [n.d.]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Multiple numbers
This collection consists of ca. 815 items, chiefly correspondence by and to John Randolph of Roanoke.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired through gift, purchase and loan, ca. 1930-present.
Biographical/Historical Information
John Randolph was born on June 2, 1773, at Cawsons, a plantation in Prince George County, Virginia. He was educated at the College of New Jersey, Columbia College, and the College of William and Mary. He studied law with his relative Edmund Randolph, then attorney general of the United States.
Randolph was elected to the House of Representatives in 1799 and served in Congress almost continually until his death in 1833. He was a brilliant orator and was known and feared for his biting and sarcastic wit. An outspoken champion of individual liberty, he staunchly defended the Constitution and states' rights, and his views were influential in the South long after his death.
By 1801 Randolph was chairman of the powerful Ways and Means Committee. He was one of the managers appointed by the House of Representatives in January 1804 to conduct the impeachment proceedings against Judge John Pickering, and in December of the same year against Supreme Court Justice Samuel.
On principle Randolph opposed President Thomas Jefferson's attempt to obtain West Florida from Spain. He voted against the Embargo Act of 1807 and opposed the War of 1812. This cost him reelection, but he was back in the House two years later, in 1815. An ardent states' rights advocate, Randolph denounced the tariff of 1816, which he believed harmed Southern interests, and opposed chartering the Second Bank of the United States. In 1820 he denounced the Missouri Compromise as a cowardly surrender to antislavery agitators. His impassioned denunciations of Henry Clay and John Quincy Adams led to a duel (1826) with Clay.
Randolph was appointed to the United States Senate on December 8, 1825, to fill the vacancy caused by the resignation of James Barbour; he served from December 26, 1825, to March 3, 1827 and was unsuccessful in his bid for reelection in 1827. He was elected to the House and served from 1827 to 1829.
He was a member of the Virginia constitutional convention at Richmond in 1829. President Andrew appointed Randolph United States Minister to Russia in 1830. His health deteriorated soon after his arrival in St. Petersburg, so he returned home in 1831. Following his return he denounced Jackson's proclamation against nullification. Randolph was elected to the Twenty-third Congress and served from March 4, 1833, until his death in Philadelphia, Pa., May 24, 1833. He was buried at his residence, 'Roanoke,' in Charlotte County, Virginia and later re-interred at 'Hollywood,' Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 815 items, chiefly correspondence by and to John Randolph of Roanoke.
Correspondents include: Harmanus Bleecker; Edward Booker; John Brockenbrough; Delia Forman Bryan; Joseph Bryan; Thomas Marsh Forman Bryan; Joseph Butterworth; Henry Carrington; Joseph A. Clay; Anne Frances Bland Tucker Coalter; Elizabeth Tucker Coalter; John Coalter; Alexander Dallas; Susan Wheeler Decatur; William Eustis; John Floyd; James Mercer Garnett; Francis Walker Gilmer; Peachy R. Gilmer; Jacob Harvey; George Hay; Thomas Jefferson; Benjamin Watkins Leigh; Richard E. Meade; James Monroe; Anne Cary Randolph Morris; David Parish; John Henry Purviance; John St. George Randolph; Judith Randolph; Theodorick Randolph; Tudor Randolph; Henry Middleton Rutledge; John S. Skinner; Richard Stanford; Andrew Stevenson; Creed Taylor; John Taylor; Henry St. George Tucker; Nathaniel Beverley Tucker; St. George Tucker; Martin Van Buren; Daniel Webster; Micajah Woods.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series. Series I: Letters and Documents, is arranged chronologically. Series II: Prints.
Contents List
- Series I: Letters and Documents
  - St. George Tucker to Richard, Theodorick and John Randolph, 1781 July 11, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - St. George Tucker to Theodorick and John Randolph, 1787 April 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; notes by John Randolph on p. 2;with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - St. George Tucker to [Richard, Theodorick and John Randolph], 1787 December 17, ALS, 1 p. #3400. (Box-folder 1:3)
    Mentions the birth of their step-sister.
  - John Randolph to St. George Tucker, 1788 January 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #6004. (Box-folder 1:4)
  - St. George Tucker to Theodorick and John Randolph, 1788 June 29, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:5)
  - St. George Tucker to Theodorick and John Randolph, 1788 August 13, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l.; with address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:6)
  - St. George Tucker to Theodorick and John Randolph, 1789 November 26, ALS, 1 p.; with attached partial address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond, VA. #3400. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - John Randolph to Anne Frances Bland (Tucker) Coalter, 1791 August 8, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 1:8)
  - St. George Tucker to [John Randolph], 1791 August 1[8], ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. #3400. (Box-folder 1:9)
  - John Randolph to St. George Tucker, 1794 March 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #10392. (Box-folder 1:10)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, [1796 September 25], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Frances Tucker to John Randolph, [17]98 May 27, L, 3 pp.; typescript only, location of original unknown. #2118. (Box-folder 1:12)
  - John Randolph to Daniel Cole, [1798] May 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #8428-c. (Box-folder 1:13)
  - John Randolph to Creed Taylor, [1798] September 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #1232. (Box-folder 1:14)
  - [Anne Frances] Bland Tucker [Coalter] to John Randolph, [17]98 December 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #2118. (Box-folder 1:15)
  - John Randolph to Judith Randolph, [1799 or 1800] April 19, ALS, 6 pp. on 2 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - John Randolph to Judith Randolph, [1799 or 1800] April 20, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. #3400. (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Jno Wickham to John Randolph, 1800 January 16, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, January 16. #3339. (Box-folder 1:18)
  - John Randolph to Miss [Anne Frances Bland] Tucker [Coalter,], [1800] July 28, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:19)
  - John Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1801 July 25, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #1398. (Box-folder 1:20)
  - John Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1801 October 16, ALS, fragment, 1 p.; with attached partial address leaf; docketed. #1232. (Box-folder 1:21)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1801 December 5, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:22)
  - John Randolph to "Members of the Committee of Ways and Means," [ca. 1801-1804], ADS, 1 p.; #3400. (Box-folder 1:23)
  - John Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1802 January 31, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #1398. (Box-folder 1:24)
  - John Randolph to [Britt Randolph, Jr.], 1802 April 8, ALS, 1 p. #8428-a. (Box-folder 1:25)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [Richard E.] Meade, 1802 September 5, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:26)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, [1802] September [10], ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:27)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1802 September 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:28)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Richard E. Meade, 1802 October 2, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:29)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1802 October 10, ALS, 1 p.; address on verso. #3400. (Box-folder 1:30)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. [Anne Frances Bland (Tucker)] Coalter, 1802 November 14, ALS, 2 pp.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:31)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, Wednesday night, [ca. 1802-1807], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #10216. (Box-folder 1:32)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Dr. [Richard E. Meade], Sunday night, [ca. 1802-1807], ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:33)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Richard E. Meade, [ca. 1802-1807], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:34)
  - John Randolph to William B[ranch] Giles, 1803 January 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #3950. (Box-folder 1:35)
  - John Randolph to [Anne Frances Bland (Tucker)] Coalter, 1803 January 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 1:36)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1803 February 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; mylar. #10126. (Box-folder 1:37)
  - John Randolph to William Jones, 1803 March 5, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Georgetown, March 5. #8428-d. (Box-folder 1:38)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1803 April 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:39)
  - J[udith] R[andolph] to John Randolph, 1803 April 14, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:40)
  - J[udith] R[andolph] to John Randolph, [1803?] April 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:41)
  - J[udith] R[andolph] to John Randolph, [1803 April 23], ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:42)
  - J[udith] R[andolph] to [John Randolph], [1803 April 23], ALS, 1 p.; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:43)
  - J[udith] R[andolph] to John Randolph, [1803? April 24], Sunday, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #3400. (Box-folder 1:44)
    Watermarked paper 1801, so possibly written in 1803, refers to traveling to "Mr. H's" as mentioned in her letter of April 23.
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1803 April -, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:45)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1803 May 1, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:46)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [Anne Frances Bland (Tucker)] Coalter, 1803 May 3, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, May 4. #3400. (Box-folder 1:47)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1803 December 27, ALS, 3 pp., including attached address leaf, text on p. 3 partially obscured by two small holes. #15289. (Box-folder 1:48)
    Randolph writes to the Amelia County physician regarding the latter's dejection and explaining "I am too well apprized, my dear friend, that our passions govern us, to make a senseless parade of governing them. I have proved the truth of this opinion too often, & too fatally, not to rank those who advocate the opposite doctrine in the class of knaves or fools, or of that very good sort of people, who, rather than not have something to say by way of consoling a friend in distress, condescend to advance opinions which they themselves disbelieve."
  - John Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1803, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #1398. (Box-folder 1:49)
  - John Randolph to James Madison, [1803], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; photocopy. #2988. (Box-folder 1:50)
    Original in McGregor-Madison.
  - John Coalter to [John Randolph], [before 1804, March 27], ALS, 1 p.; with attached partial address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, March 27. #3400. (Box-folder 1:51)
    Additional note signed by John Randolph Jr., so presumably before 1804.
  - John Randolph to Anne Frances Bland (Tucker) Coalter, [before 1804], September 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:52)
    Signed "John Randolph Jr.," so presumably written before 1804.
  - John Randolph to Richard Meade, [before 1804], Sunday Night, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; photostat only. #3590. (Box-folder 1:53)
  - John Randolph to Joseph Bryan, [before 1804], ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed. #3339. (Box-folder 1:54)
    Signed "John Randolph Jr."
  - John Randolph to Anne Frances Bland (Tucker) [Coalter], [before 1804], ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:55)
  - John Randolph to William Rawle, 1804 January 4, ALS, 1 p. #3620-a. (Box-folder 1:56)
  - J[ohn] Randolph to [Anne Frances Bland (Tucker)] Coalter, 1804 January 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 1:57)
    Contains the following note to Mrs. Coalter: "I am no longer jr" after his signature.
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Richard E. Meade, 1804 January 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; mylar. #10126. (Box-folder 1:58)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Dr. [Richard E.] Meade, [1804] April 3, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:59)
  - John Randolph to [Joseph Bryan], 1804 May 30, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #3400. (Box-folder 1:60)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1804 May 31, ALS, 1 pp. on 2 leaves including attached address leaf. #15289. (Box-folder 1:61)
    Randolph reports that [Joseph] Bryan has reached Savannah safely and that he himself has retired to Bizarre as he is "unfit for the world & it's society" though he would have liked to have stopped in Amelia to see Meade. He concludes with a note that Miss Vixen and her foal are doing well and a request to forward two vest patterns.
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Dr. [Richard E.] Meade, 1804 June 3, ALS, 1 p.; with address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:62)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1804 July 24, ALS, 2 pp.; with address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:63)
  - John Randolph to [Anne] Frances Bland [(Tucker)] Coalter, 1804 September 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:64)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to George Hay, [ca. 1804 October], ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; with typescript. #8428. (Box-folder 1:65)
  - John Randolph to Dr. [Richard E.] Meade, 1804 December 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; mylar. #10126. (Box-folder 1:66)
  - John Randolph to Alexander Dallas, 1804 December 14, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #7224. (Box-folder 1:67)
  - John Randolph to John Hollins, 1805 January 9, ALS, 1 p. #6489. (Box-folder 1:68)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1805 January 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, January 23. #10126. (Box-folder 1:69)
  - John Randolph to Thomas Jefferson, 1805 March 4, ALS, 1 p; with attached address leaf; docketed; photocopy, original in Thomas Jefferson papers. #11319. (Box-folder 1:70)
  - J[ohn] Randolph to Mrs. [Anne Frances Bland (Tucker)] Coalter, 1805 March 6, ALS, 1 p.; with attached partial address leaf; docketed; postmarked Fredericksburg VA, March [?] and Williamsburg VA, March 11. #3400. (Box-folder 1:71)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. [Anne Frances Bland (Tucker)] Coalter, 1805 April 17, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:72)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Dr. [Richard E.] Meade, [1805] April 30, ALS, 1 p.; address on verso. #10126. (Box-folder 1:73)
  - John Randolph to "Dear Sir", 1805 June 12, ALS, 1 p. #9371-q. (Box-folder 1:74)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [Elizabeth] Coalter, [1805] July 18, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #49. (Box-folder 1:75)
  - De Witt Clinton to John Randolph 1805 November 23, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. #5718-e. (Box-folder 1:75A)
    Clinton sends a letter of introduction for New York Representative Peter Sailly.
  - John Randolph speeches written by his secretary, 1805-1810, AMs copy, 216 pp. on 56 l. #1893. (Box-folder 1:76)
  - George Clinton to [John Randolph] 1806 January 17, ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. #5718-e. (Box-folder 1:76A)
    Requests Randolph come to dinner on the next day.
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 April 27, ALS, 5 pp. on 4 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:77)
  - Joseph Butterworth to John Randolph, 1806 May 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked 1806 May 7. #3920. (Box-folder 1:78)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 May 11, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:79)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 May -, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, May 19. #1883. (Box-folder 1:80)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 June 4, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:81)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 June 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:82)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 July 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 1:83)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 July 5, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:84)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 September 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 1:85)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1806 October 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 1:86)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 October 28, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:87)
    #1883.
  - Unidentified to [Michal Wallace], 1806 November 6, ALS, 2 pp.; photostat only, location of original unknown. #2118. (Box-folder 1:88)
  - John Randolph to Caesar Augustus Rodney, 1806 November 20, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #10937-a. (Box-folder 1:89)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1806 [i.e. 1807] January 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:90)
    Possibly misdated and written in 1807 rather than 1806.
  - John Randolph to George Hay, 1806 [i.e. 1807] January 3, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. #3339. (Box-folder 1:91)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1806 [i.e. 1807] January 3, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; photostat only. #3590. (Box-folder 1:92)
    Contains note written by Randolph regarding his mistake of dating his letter 1806 rather than 1807.
  - John Randolph to Joseph Scott, 1806 [i.e. 1807] January 12, ALS, 1 p. #6489. (Box-folder 1:93)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1807 March 7, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 1:94)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1807 March 17, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:95)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1807 April 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:96)
  - John Randolph to Thomas Newton, 1807 May 1, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #6489. (Box-folder 1:97)
  - John Randolph to Dr. [Richard E.] Meade, [1807] May 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:98)
  - John Randolph to John H. Purviance, 1807 May 30, ALS, 1 p.; with notes on verso in unidentified hand. #6489. (Box-folder 1:99)
    Contains an unconfirmed reference to the treason trial of Aaron Burr ("Col. B."), and refers to "Gen. Wilkinson."
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1807 August 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 1:100)
  - John Randolph to John Taylor, 1807 September 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #10054. (Box-folder 1:101)
  - J[udith] R[andolph] to John Randolph, [1807] September 28, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 1:102)
  - John Randolph to Richard E. Meade, 1807 November 5, ALS, 1 p.; address on verso; photostat only, location of original unknown. #3590. (Box-folder 1:103)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Richard E. Meade, 1807 December 5, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #10126. (Box-folder 1:104)
  - John Randolph to Edward Booker, 1808 January 10, ALS, 1 p. #7586. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - John Randolph to Joseph Clay, 1808 February 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Georgetown, February 15. #6015. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - John Randolph to George Hay, 1808 February 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3339. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - John Randolph to John Coalter, 1808 March 29, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John Randolph to John Coalter, 1808 April 11, ALS, 1 p. #8415. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1808 May 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - John Coalter to John Randolph, [1808] May 11, ALS, 6 pp. on 2 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 2:7)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1808 May 27, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 2:8)
  - St. George Tucker to John Randolph, 1808 June 14, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Williamsburg VA, June [?]. #3400. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1808 July 3, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to James Mercer Garnett, 1808 July 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 2:11)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1808 August 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 2:12)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1808 August 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 3 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:13)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1808 September 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 2:14)
  - St. George Tucker to John Randolph, 1808 September 21, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 2:15)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1808 September 25, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:16)
  - John Randolph to [Anne] F[rances] Bland [(Tucker)] Coalter, 1808 November 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 2:17)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [Anne] Frances Bland [(Tucker)] Coalter, 1809 January 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - John Randolph to [Anne Frances] Bland [(Tucker)] Coalter, 1809 February 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 2:19)
  - John Randolph to John Henry Purviance, 1809 February 17, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #8739-a. (Box-folder 2:20)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to John Coalter, 1809 February 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 2:21)
  - "To the Freeholders of Caroline, Essex, King and Queen and King-William," 1809 February 25, D, 3 pp.; addressed by James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Fanny Bland Coalter to John Randolph, 1809 March 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 2:23)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1809 March 18, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1809 April 4, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:25)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1809 April 9, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 2:26)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1809 April 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 2:27)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1809 May 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:28)
  - John Randolph to William Eustis, 1809 June 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #7224. (Box-folder 2:29)
    Brittle along folds.
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1809 June 12, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 2:30)